因此，我希望您在项目目录中创建一个新目录，并且
So I want you to make a new directory
inside of your project directory, and
我们会把这一网络联系成网络
we're gonna call this one networking,
cd into networking.
我们来做吧
And, Let's do this.
我们会说 npm 的 init - y
We're gonna say npm init -y.
我们会说 npm install mongodb
And we're gonna say npm install mongodb
@hapi/ hapi，并且我们需要 hapi-pino。
@hapi/hapi, and we need hapi-pino.
P -I-N-O，我认为这就是我们需要的，让我看看。
P-I-N-O, I think that's all we need,
let me check.
是啊应该很好
Yeah, that should be good.
这将需要第二个时间来安装其中一些东西。
That'll take a second to
install a few of those things.
在这里，我要创建一个 index.js 。
And here, I'm going to create an index.js.
其实我们是从档案探险家来的
Actually let's just do it
here from the file explorer.
把剩下的都关了
Close the rest of those.
在网络里我们会说新文件
And here inside the networking,
we're gonna say New File and
这将被称为 index.js 。
this is gonna be called index.js.
我要来这里和 Docker联网
And I'm gonna come back over
here to networking with Docker,
我们会把所有东西都复制到这里
and we are going to copy everything here.
它是一个比较复杂的应用程序，它与一个数据库进行对话。
It's a little bit more complicated app,
it talks to a database.
你也不一定要明白
Again, you don't necessarily
have to understand
来了解我们在这里所做的事情
this to understand what we are doing here.
只是暂时让你穿过这里的代码
But to just momentarily walk
you through the code here.
它将通过官方的驾驶员连接到蒙戈 db 。
It's going to connect to mongodb
via the official driver.
让我们确保正确的版本。
Let's make sure that we
get the right version.
那是我最后一次的大问题
That was a big problem for me last time.
当你晚上做 npm 的安装时
To be safe, when you're doing npm install,
你想做 @hapi/hapi，
You wanna do @hapi/hapi,
hapi-pino 和 mongodb@3。
hapi-pino and mongodb@3.
只是为了确保你能找到正确的司机
Just to make sure that you're
getting the correct driver for this.
我们甚至说 @3.3。
Let's even say @3.3.
我们就这么做吧
Let's just do that.
这将使您的 mongodb 降级到 3.35。
So this will downgrade
your mongodb to 3.35.
我们走了， 3.4 可能会起作用，可能不会，我们不会去检查的。
There we go, 3.4 might work,
it might not, we're not going to check.
好的回去吧
Okay, going back.
我们要启动一个单台服务器，它将会实例化 MongoClient。
We're gonna start a hapi server,
it's going to instantiate a MongoClient.
如果我提供一个环境变量的话它也会连接到
And it's going to connect to either if
I provide an environmental variable of
它会连接到 Mongo 连接串
it Mongo connection string
it'll connect to that.
否则它将缺省连接到本地
Otherwise it's going to default
to connecting to just a locally
运行 MongoDB。
running MongoDB.
如果你在笔记本电脑上运行 MongoD ，你可以在本地运行。
So you could run this locally if
you're running MongoD, on your laptop.
好的，我们会给它一个数据库的数据库名称，我们会给它一个集合的名字。
Okay, we'll give it a DB name of dockerApp
and we'll give a collection name of count.
每当你点击这个斜杠的路径时
Anytime that you hit
the slash route it's going
说我有多少项目，我叫它什么 ?
to say how many items do I have in my,
what do I call it?
盘点集合。
Count collection.
所以，集合就像 SQL 术语中的表格，对吧 ?
So collections are like
tables in SQL terms, right?
数据库是数据库对吧
And databases are databases, right?
所以每当你打电话给我
So and then whenever you call /add,
它只会插入一个空虚的物体对吧
it's going to insert just
a literally empty object, right?
那就得有个 ID
Which is just gonna have an ID.
所以要做的就是要不断地把东西加进去
So that's all it's gonna do is it's
just going to continually add things to
您的数据库。
your database.
基本上是最好的应用
Basically, the best application ever.
我支持这项工作。
I stand by this work.
不我开玩笑的
No, I'm just kidding.
就这样了真的就这样
That's it, yeah, that's really just it.
好了又来了你可以说煮的是蒙哥 db
Okay, and again, you could just
say brew install mongodb, and
然后在后台运行 mongod 。
then run mongod in the background.
所有这些都是正常的，那就好了，但是
All this would just work and
that'd be fine, but
我们要用集装箱来做
we're gonna do it with containers.
恩，这就是我在这儿的，好的， npm-install mongodb@3.3，
Yeah, that's actually what I have here,
okay, npm-install mongodb@3.3,
这就是我们想要的
so that's what we want.
所以如果你有问题，请确保 mongo 3.3 而不是 3.4。
So if you're having issues,
make sure you have mongo 3.3 and not 3.4.
好，现在我们要做的是，我们是否需要给它一个 Docker 文件。
Okay, now what we're going to do,
Is we need to give it a Docker file.
因此，任何旧的 Docker 文件都将正常运行。
So really any old Docker
file is gonna work.
所以我们就复制一个我们应该得到的
So let's just copy the one from the,
Which one should we get,
而不是卷，让我们从更复杂的节点应用中进行操作。
not the volumes, let's do it from
the more complicated node app.
不是那个那个
Not that one, this one.
我们要把它复制到一个新的 Docker 文件中。
And we're just going to copy that
into a new Docker file here.
基本上，我们只需要一个工作节点应用程序。
Basically, we just need
a working node application.
因此，这一操作会复制所有内容，运行 npm 安装。
So this one that does, copies
everything over, run the npm install.
不需要曝光，您可以删除。
Don't need the expose,
you can delete that.
然后在此命令节点， index.js， right?
Then the command here of node,
index.js, right?
此处的关键是我们只需在工作中启动节点应用程序
The key here is that we just need to
start the node application in a working
环境。
environment.
所以我要到这里去
So I'm going to come
in here to where am I?
我在联网
I'm in networking.
所以我要说 docker build -- tag 和
So I'm going to say docker build --tag and
我们会把这个叫做 " 带蒙戈 " 之类的
we'll call this node-with-mongo or
something like that.
你可以随便给它打个电话
You can call it whatever you want.
我在这里叫什么
What do I call here?
App - with-mongo ，因此我们将坚持使用 mongo应用程序。
App-with-mongo, so
we'll stick to app-with-mongo.
那得花第二个
That'll take a second to build.
然后把它包装好，准备好去，然后我们就去了。
And then it should be packaged up and
ready to go, and there we go.
现在我们要运行这个应用
So now we're going to run this app and
连接到正在运行的其他数据库。
connect to the other
database that's running.
所以我们会说 docker run -p 3000:3000
So we're gonna say,
docker run -p 3000:3000
--network=app-net --env，
--network=app-net --env,
我们得告诉它在哪里连接对吧
we have to tell it where to connect,
right?
所以我们要
So we're gonna
表示 MONGO_CONNECTION_STRING
say MONGO_CONNECTION_STRING
=mongodb://db:27017。
=mongodb://db:27017.
再记住，如果你把 db 放在一起，它就会知道因为它们在
Again, remember, if you put db,
it's going to know because they're on
将数据库转至数据库容器的相同网络，我们将其命名为 cuz 。
the same network that db goes over to
the db container, cuz we named it.
然后我们要用 " mongo " 来运行它，或者
And then we're gonna run
it with app-with-mongo, or
不管你叫什么容器
whatever you called your container.
我想我的笔记其实是说我的应用
I think my notes actually
say my app-with-mongo,
只要你把它叫做一样东西就不重要了
as long as you call it the same thing,
it doesn't actually matter.
因此，您可以看到它已正确启动。
So you can see it started up correctly.
现在如果我去本地主机 3000
And now if I go over
here to local host 3000,
您可以看到它有此计数值。
you can see that it has this count number.
我能把它做大吗
Can I make that bigger?
我能
I can.
这就是我们所期望的。
So that's what we expect.
它现在什么都没收好
It has nothing in that
collection right now.
如果我打开 / 添加，那么它会说，很酷，我插了些东西。
If I open it with /add, then it's
gonna say, cool, I inserted something.
现在，如果我返回到另一个并刷新，那么您可以看到其计数为 1。
And now if I go back to the other one and
refresh, you can see that its count is 1.
或者我到这里来一次又一次刷新几次
Or if I come back over here and
just hit refresh a bunch of times.
我回到这里 /，你可以看到我现在有 18 个项目在数据库里。
And I go back over here to /, you can
see now I have 18 items in the database.
所以现在我有一个集装箱
So now I have one container,
与 MangobDB 容器交谈的应用程序 - mango 容器。
the app-with-mango container
talking to the MangoDB container.
他们通过我们为自己建立的应用网络来做。
They're doing it via the app network
that we set up for ourselves.
所以我意识到这有点麻烦，对吧 ?
So I recognize this is a bit
burdensome to do, right?
建立网络不是很有趣的
It's not very fun to
set up the network and
确保所有网络都在交谈。
make sure all the networks
are talking to each other.
如果有一个工具为我们做了这些东西，那就更好了。
It'd be better if there was a tool
that just did all this stuff for us.
有但你可以把我的教学风格
There is, but you can kind of
get my teaching style where I
让你感受痛苦然后我想给你一个解决疼痛的工具
want you to feel the pain and then I want
to give you the tool that solves the pain.
我不想给你一个解决痛苦的工具
And I don't want to give you the tool that
solves the pain before you understand why
你先做个烂事对吧
something sucks first, right?
我想先吸点东西
I wanted something to suck first.
然后我想让你为
And then I want you to be happy for
解决这件事的工具对吧
the tool that solves the thing that sucks,
right?
接下来我们要谈的是 Docker Compose。
So the next thing we're going
to talk about is Docker Compose.
Docker Compose 会把所有这些东西都用在你的盒子里
And Docker Compose takes care of all this
stuff for you just kind of out of the box.